Marcelo Tomazini

Senior Developer

I'm a developer with twelve years of software development experience. I have experience in companies that include development consulting, payment methods, health care providers and telecom market. My main knowledge of technology is Java; some experience with Docker, Kubernetes, Groovy, Go, Python, PHP, Delphi, SpringBoot, MySQL, Oracle, Postgres, Linux, Web services, Ansible, CSS, HTML, Javascript, JQuery, Node.js, ReactJs, Gradle, Maven and Jenkins. I have great interest in learning new technologies, given it is useful to build value.

Experience

Developer, Avenue Code (Oct 2023)

I joined Avenue Code to integrate a team to work for Ebay. We take care of some services related to negotiation and buyer commitment to a purchase. The projects are written in java and use a lot of internal frameworks.

Developer, Truelogic Software (Oct 2022 - Sep 2023)

I joined Truelogic to integrate a team to work for Uber. We take care of some migrations from legacy systems written in Python to the new versions in Go and the project's modernization, for example, migrating from thrift to grpc. Also worked in the implementation of other features and integrations.

Developer Consultant, Thoughtworks (Sep 2021 – Sep 2022)

As a consultant for Thoughtworks, I had the chance to work for huge companies, helping them to evolve their applications. I've developed web services using languages/frameworks like Go, Java, SpringBoot and web applications using React, deploying them in a kubernetes cluster, practicing continuous integration and trying to implement continuous deploy. And doing all of this in a team using Scrum as the main agile technique

Developer, Objective (Apr 2011 – Aug 2021)

I joined Objective to integrate the team that would take care of a large desktop system for telecom companies using Java. Also building web services to integrate with this system. Helped with the migration of this system from Java 6 to Java 11. Worked in the DevSecOps area helping with the implementation of CI/CD in many projects using Jenkins as the main tool for this process, also being an administrator of the Jenkins instance as well as the kubernete's cluster. I've helped to scale the test execution for this large project (almost 50.000 functional tests). Implemented the infrastructure as code concept using tools like Ansible, Terraform, Helm.

Developer, Benner (Jan 2010 – Dec 2010)

I joined Benner to integrate the team that would take care of their software for health care providers built in Delphi with a database layer abstraction that at the end of the day would interface with Oracle or MS SQL Server.

Developer, Oliver Media (Sep 2009 – Dec 2009)

I joined Oliver Media to integrate the team that would build institutional websites using HTML, PHP, Javascript and CSS.

Developer, Atual Consultoria e Sistemas (Jan 2009 – Aug 2009)

I joined Atual Consultoria e Sistemas to integrate the team that would take care of the company's ERP built with Delphi that handles different kinds of businesses for small local companies.

Skills

- Programming Languages: Java, Groovy, Go, Python, PHP, Delphi
- Databases: MySQL, Oracle, Postgres, MongoDB
- Testing Tools: JUnit, Puppeteer
- Version Tools: SVN, Git
- CI/CD Tools: Jenkins
- Project Management Tools: GitHub, Bitbucket, Trello, Jira Methodologies: TDD, Pair Programming, Kanban, Agile
- Cloud Infrastructure: AWS, Azure

Education

- Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science, UEM Maringá (2007 - 2012)